hello in this video I will be explaining
to you the lady disclosed slack
vulnerability regarding the term server
that allowed accessing the internal
network and was awarded 3.5 K dollars
first let's see how the vulnerability
actually worked in the JSON response to
a request of creating a voice call on
slack the hunter noticed a JSON object
called turn alpha with parameters
username and password and obviously if
you are a hunter and you see a clear
text credentials in your response you
know it might be a good lead but of
course first you need to know where to
use these credentials
and actually the turn server happens to
be on a slack - core subdomain which was
not listed as in scope asset on hacker
ones page that's the domain that slug
has it's called infrastructure on
unlikely the researcher carried on
because he knew the impact of this
potential vulnerability and to
understand it better let's see what the
turn server actually is so one Alice
wants to send a text message to Bob via
slug she sends the text message to the
slack HTTP server and then when Bob
requests his messages from the HTTP
server he gets it back no problem at all
however when we want to make a voice
call we do not want to be going through
the HTTP server because it will cause a
big latency and that's something we have
to avoid so in such scenarios we want to
establish a direct UDP connection to
stream a media to another client and
when we are in the same local area
network it's no problem we can just send
the data one to another it's easy and
simple however when we are a little bit
further from each other things start to
get complicated because there are nuts
and firewalls which make it not as easy
to establish a direct connection between
a clients and actually a terror server
happens to be one of the ways around
this because Taryn stands for traversal
using realize around nut we're not
stands for network address translation
so it's used to
preserve public address space and it
allows internal network with many local
IP addresses to have much less public IP
addresses so it's a good thing but when
we want to establish a direct connection
it becomes a little bit difficult
especially when we have specific type of
symmetric nut which means that for every
connection it assigns a unique IP and
port address so that's where the Terran
server comes into play it's a kind of a
last resort where others ways of
connection fail it's something that both
Alice and Bob can connect to and it
practices the traffic from one to
another and there are more servers
involved in a initiation of this
connection via turn server and actually
the request we saw earlier with the turn
server credentials horse name and a few
other parameters was one of the requests
in this initiation process and because
the turn server needs some kind of
authentication and the client needs a
direct connection it's actually nothing
wrong in the fact that the username and
password were sent in plain text to the
client it's actually how it works but
rather what the vulnerability was here
is that term server is obviously
connected to slack internal network and
by design it allows the client to make a
connection and proxy is request to an
address specified by the client which
means the client can request to proxy
his traffic to the internal network and
it's actually what the vulnerability was
here the attacker asked the Tara server
to proxy his traffic to the internal
network and then he could for example
request metadata and get the credentials
to the server so according to the RFC
the term server should have a blacklist
of IP addresses that the clients are not
allowed to proxy to and that's exactly
what the vulnerability was there there
was no blacklist and the client could
proxy everywhere
moreover the functionality of voice
calls only needed the UDP protocol but
the term server
so aloud the TCP protocol to be proxied
which of course increased the impact a
lot so that's the high-level overview of
the vulnerability here if you want to
get into detail of how does the turn
server work and why it's necessary I
will give you specific links in the
description an important takeaway from
this report is a good cooperation of the
reporter with the slug company he
provided them with a good details of how
to fix this vulnerability and multiple
times verified fixes deployed by the
company I'm convinced it has increased
the bounty he was awarded it was three
point five K and also we can see that he
uses some custom tools specifically
built to exploit the turn server and
actually I've done some research and
happened out that this researcher Sandra
Gucci is a CEO of enable security
company and they specify in identifying
vulnerabilities in WebRTC and void
functionalities so another takeaway here
is that it's a good idea to find a niche
built a good tool set around it
and be an expert in some area this
vulnerability is on a little bit lower
network level than most of the web bugs
but I hope you now understand it a
little bit better if you have leave a
like thank you